MoMA PS1 Archives
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series I: Curatorial and Exhibition Records, (19682009)
  - Subseries I.A: General Files, (19702009)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Mary Heilmann, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.1998)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Rebecca Horn, 1997; Background materials on Horn with some correspondence apparently inviting her to participate in the reopening installations. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.1999)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Judith Hudson, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2000)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Ilya Kabokov, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2001)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Tobi Kahn, circa 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2002)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Seth Kelly, 1997; Some Young New Yorkers(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2003)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Patrick Killoran, 10/22/1997; One piece of correspondence only. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2004)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Bill Komoski, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2005)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Julian Laverdiere, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2006)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Fabian Marcaccio, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2007)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Mabou Mines, 1997; Heaven: Public View, Private View(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2008)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Matt Mullican, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2009)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Antonio Muntadas, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2010)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Hironori Murai, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2011)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Bruce Nauman, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2012)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Olaf Nicolai, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2013)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Richard Nonas, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2014)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Dennis Oppenheim, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2015)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Eric Orr, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 124, Folder I.A.2016)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Carl Ostendarp, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2017)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Tony Oursler, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2018)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Laura Owens, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2019)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Manfred Pernice, 1997-1998; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2020)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Cindy Poorbaugh, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2021)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Lucio Pozzi, 1997-1998; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2022)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Rebecca Quaytman, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2023)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: David Reed, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2024)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Pedro Cabrita Reis, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2025)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Tobias Rehberger, 1997; Heaven: Public View, Private View(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2026)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Pipilotti Rist, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2027)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Jason Rosenberg, 1997; Some Young New Yorkers(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2028)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Robert Ryman, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2029)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Alan Saret, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2030)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Julia Scher, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2031)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Julian Schnabel, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2032)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Barbara Schreiber, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2033)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Richard Serra, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2034)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Katherina Sieverding, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2035)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Jack Smith, 1997; Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2036)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Keith Sonnnier, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 125, Folder I.A.2037)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Lawre Stone, 1997; Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2038)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Sarah Sze, 1997; Some Young New Yorkers(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2039)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Sam Taylor-Wood, 1997-1998; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2040)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: James Turrell, 1998; James Turrell: "Meeting"(October 26, 1986-[ongoing]): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2041)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Merrill Wagner, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2042)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Nari Ward, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2043)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Lawrence Weiner, 1997-1998; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2044)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Rachel Whiteread, 1997; Includes loan form. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan form. (Box 126, Folder I.A.2045)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Clara Williams, 1997; Some Young New Yorkers(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2046)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Robert Wogan, 1997; Unlabelled VHS cassette only. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2047)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Robert Wogan, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2048)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Lynn Yamamoto, 1997; Lynne Yamamoto: Selected Works(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2049)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Chen Zhen, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2050)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Andrea Zittel, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2051)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: "Other Young Options", 1997; Small amount of materials on artists apparently considered for the exhibition. Some Young New Yorkers(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 126, Folder I.A.2052)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Correspondence, 1997; Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2053)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Floor Plans and Installation Materials, 1997; P.S. 1 Reopening(October 26, 1997): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2054)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Artwork Slides, 1997; Slides of previous works by numerous artists involved in the reopening exhibitions; in alphabetic order by artist name. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): Art and Event Photographs (Box 127, Folder I.A.2055)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: Miscellaneous Slides, 1997; Slides of artworks from various artists, some with past associations with P.S. 1, gathered perhaps in relation to the stairwell "vertical painting series" initiated with the reopening. (Box 127, Folder I.A.2056)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: "Stairwell Painters", 1997; Small amount of notes and a list of possible artists. Vertical Painting Show(October 29, 1997-June 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2057)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: "Loan Agreement Forms", 1997; Loan forms signed by Martin fritz and individual artists, with minimal artwork information; separate from the more standardized loan forms more commonly used. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2058)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: "Other Stuff", 1997; Miscellaneous documents with some correspondence. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2059)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: "Writing Project", 1997; Texts by numerous writers commenting on artists, specific artworks, and P.S. 1 itself, created as part of the opening. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2060)
    - Reopening Artist and Installation Files: "Writing Project", 1997; Texts by numerous writers commenting on artists, specific artworks, and P.S. 1 itself, created as part of the opening. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 127, Folder I.A.2061)
    - "Writer's Project", 1997; Correspondence and memos regarding a project inviting writers into P.S. 1 to write, on the spot, their responses to artworks and engage in a public dialog as part of the reopening. (Box 127, Folder I.A.2062)
    - Writer's Project Texts, circa 1997; Short texts by numerous different people from a project inviting writers into P.S. 1 to write, on the spot, their responses to artworks and engage in a public dialogue; coordinated with the reopening. (Box 127, Folder I.A.2063)
    - "Marika Wachtmeister Project", 1997; Materials regarding an unrealized project, planned by Wachtmeister, for three artists exploiting P.S. 1's basement for the 1997 reopening. (Box 127, Folder I.A.2064)
    - Nari Ward Exhibition Materials, 1943-1945; Miscellaneous public school forms and documents, apparently found within P.S. 1 and dating from its days as an active public school; used (or considered for use) as part of an installation in the attic by Nari Ward during the re-opening exhibitions. Includes exam sheets, lesson plans, new clippings, blank forms, student artwork, and scrapbook pages. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 717, Folder I.A.2065*)
    - Nari Ward Exhibition Materials, 1942-1945; Miscellaneous public school forms and documents, apparently found within P.S. 1 and dating from its days as an active public school; used (or considered for use) as part of an installation in the attic by Nari Ward during the re-opening exhibitions. Includes class materials and teacher reviews, memos, and other documents. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 128, Folder I.A.2066)
    - Nari Ward Exhibition Materials, 1942-1945; Miscellaneous public school forms and documents, apparently found within P.S. 1 and dating from its days as an active public school; used (or considered for use) as part of an installation in the attic by Nari Ward during the re-opening exhibitions. Includes miscellaneous printed materials. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 128, Folder I.A.2067)
    - Reopening Loan Forms, 1997-1998; Loan forms, arranged alphabetically by artist, for works in the reopening series of exhibitions; with some correspondence. Jackie Winsor(January 17-March 10, 1988): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Gordon Matta-Clark: Reorganizing Structure by Drawing Through It(April 26-August 30, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 128, Folder I.A.2068)
    - Reopening and Other Loan Forms, 1997-1998; Loan forms, arranged alphabetically by artist, for works in the reopening series of exhibitions and later shows; with some correspondence. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Cities on the Move 3(October 18, 1998-January 17, 1999): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Late Blooming(October 18, 1998-January 17, 1999): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 128, Folder I.A.2069)
    - Reopening and Later Loan Forms and Insurance Releases, 1998; Loan forms and releases from insurance coverage for various exhibitions from late 1997 to 1998. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation John Miller: Paintings and Sculpture(July 5-October 18, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports David Levinthal: Cowboy Corridor(September 13, 1998-January 24, 1999): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Late Blooming(October 18, 1998-January 17, 1999): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 128, Folder I.A.2070)
    - "Certificates of Insurance", 1999; Insurance certificates for works by individual artists for numerous exhibitions in the spring season.; Entire folder restricted. (Box 128, Folder I.A.2071)
    - Reopening and 1998 Loan Forms and Documents, 1997-1998; Includes loan forms, related partial checklists, and correspondence relating to multiple exhibitions. P.S. 1 Reopening(October 26, 1997): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Some Young New Yorkers II(February 15-April 12, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Projects/Installations(February 15,1998-[unknown closing date]): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Alex Katz Under the Stars: American Landscapes 1951-1995(April 26-June 21, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 129, Folder I.A.2072)
    - Lili Dujourie Artwork Damage Correspondence, 1997-2000; Correspondence, photographs, and other materials relating to the work Grey Fields; including loan and other correspondence and information on the artist. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 129, Folder I.A.2073)
    - Lili Dujourie Letter, 1998; Regarding damage to an artwork in the reopening exhibitions. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 129, Folder I.A.2074)
    - "Dujourie-Claim Zittel", 1998; Materials regarding damage to an artwork by Lili Dujourie. Reopening: Installations and Projects(October 29, 1997-February 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 129, Folder I.A.2075)
    - "Coplans Update", 1996; Correspondence. John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 129, Folder I.A.2076)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: John Coplans Travel", 1996-1997; Correspondence and materials regarding the exhibition traveling. John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): Checklist (Box 129, Folder I.A.2077)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: John Coplans", 1997; "Master" list of slides and attached list. John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): Art and Event Photographs (Box 129, Folder I.A.2078)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: John Coplans", 1997; "Extra slides-not to distribute." John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): Art and Event Photographs (Box 129, Folder I.A.2079)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: John Coplans", 1997; Includes biographical texts, budget, and other materials for the catalogue including transcript of interview between Alanna Heiss and Coplans. John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 129, Folder I.A.2080)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: John Coplans", 1997; Documents and material related to shipping and travelling of the exhibition. John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 129, Folder I.A.2081)
    - "John Coplans Touring Information Packet", 1997; Packet of images and exhibition description sent out to advertise the show for tour. John Coplans: A Self-Portrait(October 29, 1997-March 29, 1998): Checklist; Installation Photographs (Box 129, Folder I.A.2082)
    - "Jackie Winsor Returns", 1998; Notes and artwork lists on artwork returns. Jackie Winsor: Sculpture(October 29, 1997-February 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 129, Folder I.A.2083)
    - "Jackie Winsor: Silent Space", 1997-1998; Includes loan correspondence, lists of artworks preferred by Winsor and by Paula Cooper for the exhibition, and grant materials. Jackie Winsor: Sculpture(October 29, 1997-February 28, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2084)
    - Jackie Winsor Condition Reports, 1998; Jackie Winsor: Sculpture(October 29, 1997-February 28, 1998): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 130, Folder I.A.2085)
    - Jack Smith: "Book One", circa 1997; Photocopies of drawings by Smith, transcripts of interviews and recordings, with article and essay photocopies. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2086)
    - Jack Smith: "Book Two", circa 1996; Essay texts and catalogue production schedule. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2087)
    - Jack Smith: "Color Xerox", circa 1997; One reproduction of a Smith image. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2088)
    - Jack Smith: "Walkthrough", circa 1995; Four-page description of the exhibition concept and layout. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2089)
    - Jack Smith: "Travel", 1995-1997; Correspondence regarding other venues for the exhibition. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2090)
    - Jack Smith: "Exhibition", 1996; Small amount of miscellaneous documents only. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2091)
    - Jack Smith: "Slide Checklist", circa 1997; Descriptions of slide images, presumably those used for the touring informational packet. Jack Smith: Flaming Creature(October 29, 1997-March 1, 1998): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 130, Folder I.A.2092)